<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dr Kim Foale - Articles</title>
    <description>Working with community organisations and activist groups towards a fairer society using technology, communication, and education.
</description>
    <link>
    </link>
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Data is meaningless without social power</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I went to a film screening and discussion last week about Mark Duggan’s shooting by the police, and the conditions surrounding him and his family&lt;span id=&quot;hardstop&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle sidenote-number&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;sidenote&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2016/jul/18/george-amponsah-the-hard-stop-2011-riots-black-british-men&quot;&gt;Amponsah (2016). &lt;em&gt;Hard Stop&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. The event was one of the best I’ve been to. The documentary itself was authentic, engaging, and honest, showing a slice of life in London in a similar fashion to an episode of &lt;em&gt;The Wire&lt;/em&gt;. The discussion after was a real eye-opener for me: many speakers across two panels with so much to share and say. At the same time, I was rolling an idea around for this blogpost for Open Data Manchester’s &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/echo-chambers-and-post-fact-politics-how-can-we-make-evidence-and-politics-work-better-together-tickets-27755539566&quot;&gt;Echo Chambers and Post-Fact Politics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; event.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /2016/11/02/social-power-data.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2016/11/02/social-power-data.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>No False Users</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m always struck in technical meetings how quickly people dream up imaginary people. People with &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; specific needs that they didn’t know they had. A recent meeting I was in suggested that if streetlights and hospital shift patterns were connected to the Internet of Things, we could potentially make sure that nurses can get home safely at given times, by increasing lighting at the end of shifts. Or that by comparing bus times with air pollution data, we can start to think about where buses are idling and reduce respiratory disease. But of course, they’re just possibilities! We don’t know yet! Think of the potential! &lt;span class=&quot;marginnote&quot;&gt;Article length: 1131 words.&lt;br /&gt; Approx. 6 minute read.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        /2016/10/10/no-false-users.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2016/10/10/no-false-users.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>